<u>Technologies</u> | <u>Skills</u> | <u>Personal Projects</u> | <u>Education</u> | <u>Experience</u> | <u>Hobbies</u> | <u>Blog</u> (http://www.joemaidman.com/?page_id=51) | <u>Twitter (https://twitter.com/joemaidman)</u>

Joe Maidman

Software developer, former financial analyst, keen technologist.

I have followed a passion to become a software developer, completing an intensive developer bootcamp earlier this year after a decade-long career in finance. I am now a software engineer at <u>Lab49 (http://www.lab49.com/)</u>, a technology consultancy.

Technologies

This is a selection of the languages, frameworks and tools I have experience with. My goal is to use the best tool for the job and become a better developer.

Frontend ~ Typescript | javascript | jQuery | Node | React | Redux | SCSS & CSS | CSS

Backend ~ Java & Lombok | Kotlin | Spring | Hazelcast | Ruby | C# | WPF (XAML) | VBA | MySQL

Workflow ~ Git | Stash | Webpack | Jenkins | Docker

Testing ~ JUnit | Mockito | Hamcrest | Mocha | Chai | Sinon | React Storybook

Skills

I am a **curious** person who enjoys challenging accepted wisdom, questioning what I see around me, understanding how things work and people tick. I relish the unknown. My interests in technology vary and in my self-driven (sometimes slightly strange) projects, I've delved into a whole range of subjects from automated trading on betting exchanges to <u>reverse engineering RF frequencies (https://github.com/joemaidman/blades-in-motion)</u>, virtual reality and <u>cellular automata (http://gameoflife.netlify.com/)</u>. My most recent side project, <u>Bedrock</u>, is a javascript testing framework. I was curious to explore and solve the challenges involved with building a tool like this which is so critical to my day-to-day workflow.

I am used to working in an environment of constant **change** where remaining agile is a critical skill. The great volatility during the financial crisis challenged my perspective on risk and has been at least partly responsible for my decision to make such a bold career change earlier this year.

I have been fortunate to work as part of a team practising **agile methodologies** and have experience of both Kanban and Scrum, often working with colleagues distributed around the world. We put strong emphasis on implementing the principles of **clean code** and test-driven development.

Communication of ideas has been an essential part of my career to date. I relish the opportunity to meet new people and enjoy situations where communication is critical. My previous experience working as a Financial Analyst was all about **understanding businesses** and the potential impact of their decisions. I worked in a B2B environment dealing with clients on a daily basis.

Personal Projects

Project	Description	Demo	Т
Bedrock (https://github.com/joemaidman/bedrock)	javascript testing framework	<pre>npm (https://www.npmjs.com/package/bed- rock)</pre>	T ja R E
Blades in motion (https://github.com/joemaidman/blades- in-motion)	RF sniffing and replay	Blog/video (http://www.joemaidman.com/?p=317)	S C
Bloc (https://github.com/joemaidman/bloc)	Isometric multi- player building game	<pre>Demo (https://bloc- game.herokuapp.com/)/Blog (http://www.joemaidman.com/?p=540)</pre>	ja N E s N N S
Jobot (https://github.com/joemaidman/jobot)	Chat bot	Demo (http://www.joemaidman.com/?page_id=530)	jā N N F N

Education

Makers Academy, London (Jan to May 2017)

- Four-month intensive developer bootcamp
- Software Craftsmanship (SOLID principles)
- Test-driven development
- Object orientated design
- XP Values
- Principle languages Ruby and javascript

University of Reading (2003 to 2006)

• 2:1 Economics, BA (Hons)

Experience

Lab49 (Technology Consultancy), London

Graduate Software Engineer ~ *Jun 2017 to Present*

Delivering user stories and resolving defects for a client project. The code base makes extensive use of dependency injection, code generation, a functional style, separation of concerns and microservices.

Frontend ~ Typescript | javascript | Node | React | Redux | SCSS

Backend ~ Java | Kotlin | Spring | Hazelcast | Lombok

Workflow ~ Git | Webpack | Jenkins | Docker

Testing ~ JUnit | Mockito | Hamcrest | Mocha | Chai | Sinon | React Storybook

Panmure Gordon & Co (Stockbrokers), London

Investment Funds Analyst ~ *Nov 2012 to Jan 2017*

Analysing and publishing research on <u>listed investment companies</u> (https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Closed-end_fund), modelling and structuring deals including new share offerings. My experience as an investment analyst meant dealing with large and disparate data sets and combining qualitative and quantitative inputs to reach useful conclusions on a variety of sectors from technology (technology (http://www.joemaidman.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/PCT.pdf). Commercial and strategic decisions were made based on my analysis.

As well as face to face meetings and relationship building, I wrote research to encourage engagement and conceived and built a research portal and blog (WordPress) for the team to market our product.

Matrix Corporate Capital LLP (Stockbrokers), London

Investment Funds Analyst ~ *Nov 2008 to Nov 2012*

Teather & Greenwood Ltd / Landsbanki Securities (UK) Ltd (Stockbrokers), London & Iceland

Investment Funds Analyst ~ *Sep 2006 to Nov 2008*

Hobbies

- Playing the piano
- Experimenting with software and hardware
- Running & cycling
- Paddleboarding
- Gaming